These are the common filter equations in all their beautiful complexity.
这些都是卡尔曼滤波器方程 它们非常复杂
But what do they all mean.?
但是它们都是什么意思呢？
Before we jump into all the matrix math behind these equations,
我们先不探讨这些方程之后的所有矩阵数学
I'd like to just do some basic visual cleanup.
我只想清除一些基本的视觉问题
And to do that, I want to make three modifications to these equations.
为了做到这一点 我想对这些方程进行三个修改
Let's just focus on this first equation
先来看第一个方程
here so I can explain what those modifications are.
这里我可以解释一下这些修改
The first thing I'm going to do to all these equations,
我要对所有这些方程做的第一件事
is just get rid of these hats,
只是要删除这些帽子
like hats you saw at the x.
就像你在 x 看到的帽子一样
While the hat does have physical significance
虽然帽子确实具有物理意义
it indicates that this variable is an estimate.
表示这个变量是一个估计
It's not for sure. It doesn't have any mathematical significance.
但是并不确定 所以它没有任何数学意义
It's not telling us to do anything mathematically with these equations,
并没有赋予这些方程式任何数学价值
so just get rid of those for now.
所以 现在我们先删除这些帽子
Next, we're going to take all these x_k giving
接下来 我们将处理这些  x_k
k - 1 and we're going replace that with x'.
假设 k 为 -1 我们将采用 x’ 代替
Not only is this easier to look at.
这不仅看起来更容易
It's also consistent with the notation you've been using with Sebastian.
而且与 Sebastian 使用的符号保持一致
Finally we're just going to get rid of these lone k's,
最后 我们只是要除掉这些单独的 k’s
they're cluttering things up and I'd rather just look at an equation like this.
它们看起来很混乱 我只想看到这样清爽的方程
Now we have this simplified equation.
现在 我们得到了这个简化的方程式
Remember it's some math here just looks simpler.
记住 它只是让一些数学方面的东西看起来更简单
Let's take a look what happens to all of
让我们来看看 当我们应用这三步相同的清理步骤时
the call filter equations when we apply these same three cleaning steps.
所有这些滤波方程都会发生什么
We take equations which looked like these and we
我们采取类似这样的方程
convert them to equations that look like these.
然后我们将其转换成这样的方程
This representation really let's us focus on
这种方程可以让我们真正专注于
the mathematical tools we're going to need in
我们将需要的数学工具
order to make Wikipedia articles useful to us.
从而使维基百科的文章对我们有用
In fact, we can actually use certain aspects of these equations
实际上 我们可以马上使用这些方程的某些功能
right now to highlight what we're going to cover in the rest lesson.
来重点说明我们将在剩下的课上讨论什么
First, let's focus on the difference
首先 让我们专注于
between lower case and upper case, there's actually meaning there.
小写和大写字母之间的区别 这实际上是有意义的
Generally, lower case variables indicate
一般来说 小写变量表示向量
vectors while uppercase variables indicate matrices.
而大写变量表示矩阵
We'll talk more about this distinction in a minute.
我们将稍后具体谈论这个区别
We'll also talk about addition and multiplication of vectors and matrices.
我们还将讨论向量和矩阵的加法和乘法
We'll discuss one particularly special matrix called the identity
包括一个叫做身份矩阵的特殊矩阵
matrix and we'll talk about two additional important operations called the transpose,
以及另外两个称为转置的重要操作
given by this little T superscript and the Matrix inverse,
一个由这个小 T 上标和矩阵的逆表示
given by this little -1 superscript.
另一个由这个小 -1 上标表示
If this seems like an overwhelming amount of stuff to learn in a very short time,
看起来 我们似乎需要在很短的时间内学习大量内容
remember the goal here is not to memorize any of this.
但请记住 我们目标不是这些内容
The goal isn't even really to get
我们甚至并不是要记住
a conceptual understanding of linear algebra that will come with time.
线性代数的概念 随着课程深入 我们会自然掌握这些内容
The goal now is to acquire
现在 我们目标是要熟悉
a basic functional familiarity with the tool that is matrix math,
矩阵数学工具的基本功能
so that when you encounter it in future Google searches you'll know where to begin.
这样 当你在将来的谷歌搜索中遇到问题时 你将会知道从哪里开始